Guide to the Youth Document Durham and Durham Works Project Records, 1995-2008 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Interviews Series, 1995-2008 and undated, (53 boxes)
  - Durham Works. Lewis, Todd.Morrisville Director of Engineering for Red Storm Entertainment. 2000 December 5 (Box 40, Folder 449)
  - Durham Works. Thorne, Shawana. Durham. Stylist at Studio 200. 2000 Nov. 10 (Box 40, Folder 450)
  - Durham Works. Carver, John Patrick. Durham. Stylist at Jazzabelle’s. 2000 Nov. 13 (Box 40, Folder 451)
  - Durham Works. Bridges, Bruce. Durham. Co-owner of The Know Bookstore. 2000 Nov. 16 (Box 40, Folder 452)
  - Durham Works. Bravender, Terry. Durham. Pediatrician. 2000 Nov. 29 (Box 40, Folder 453)
  - Durham Works. Farrington, Monique. Durham. Basketball Player. 2000 Nov. 29 (Box 40, Folder 454)
  - Durham Works. Page, Jack. Durham. Physician. 2000 December 13 (Box 40, Folder 455)
  - Durham Works. Ricky. Durham. Owner of I Love New York Pizza. 2000 Nov. 2 (Box 41, Folder 456)
  - Durham Works. Scott. Durham. Photo Technician. 2000 Nov. 2 (Box 41, Folder 456)
  - Durham Works. Barbee, Natasha. Durham. Cosmetologist, Owner of New Beauty Solutions. 2000 Nov. 15 (Box 41, Folder 457)
  - Durham Works. Thomas, Doris. Director of John Avery Boys and Girls Club. 2000 Nov. 1 (Box 41, Folder 458)
  - Durham Works. Thomas, Larry. Durham. Radio Program Manager. 2001 Apr. 11 (Box 41, Folder 459)
  - Durham Works. Tanabe, David.Cary Hockey Player for the Carolina Hurricanes. (Box 41, Folder 460)
  - Durham Works. McCullers, Annick. Durham. Cosmetologist, Owner of Picture Perfect Salon. 2001 Spring (Box 41, Folder 461)
  - Durham Works. Banks, Sherrod.RTP Lawyer. 2001 Spring (Box 41, Folder 462)
  - Durham Works. Malley, Pamela. Durham. Manager at Kindercare. 2001 Apr. 5 (Box 41, Folder 463)
  - Durham Works. Woods, Marsha. Durham. Locksmith and Owner of Woods Lock Service. 2001 Apr. 5 (Box 41, Folder 464)
  - Durham Works. Tracy, Scott. Durham. Executive Chief. 2001 Apr. 11 (Box 41, Folder 465)
  - Durham Works. Offenburg, Chaz. Durham. Carpenter at Lowe’s Home Improvement Warehouse. 2001 Spring (Box 41, Folder 466)
  - Durham Works. Parrish, Bubba. Durham. Director of Sales at University Ford. 2001 Apr. 12 (Box 42, Folder 467)
  - Durham Works. Astrachan, Owen. Computer Scientist. (Box 42, Folder 468)
  - Durham Works. Meyers, Carol. Archaeologist. (Box 42, Folder 469)
  - Durham Works. Miller, Ray. Mechanic. (Box 42, Folder 470)
  - Durham Works. Hemwich, Alex. Computer Programmer. (Box 42, Folder 471)
  - Durham Works. Shaduck, Phil. Surgeon. (Box 42, Folder 472)
  - Durham Works. Hart, Brandon. House Painter. (Box 42, Folder 473)
  - Durham Works. Nelson, Rodney. Principal at Jordan High School. (Box 42, Folder 474)
  - Durham Works. Romero, Lucio. Construction Worker. (Box 42, Folder 475)
  - Durham Works. Borges, Hector. Police Officer. (Box 42, Folder 476)
  - Durham Works. Duke, Kenneth. Lawyer. (Box 42, Folder 477)
  - Durham Works. White, Michelle. Dancer. (Box 43, Folder 478)
  - Durham Works. Restaurant Manager. (Box 43, Folder 479)
  - Durham Works. Karasek, Brian. Military Recruiter. (Box 43, Folder 480)
  - Durham Works. Dawson, Lois. Singer. (Box 43, Folder 481)
  - Durham Works. Anglin, Kim. Accountant. (Box 43, Folder 482)
  - Durham Works. Chastain, Pamela. Graphic Designer. (Box 43, Folder 483)
  - Community Stories. Wilcox, Eric, et al. Baseball Player. 1999 July 29 (Box 43, Folder 484)
  - Techno-Durham. Dominguez, Martin. Computer Programmer.2000 (Box 43, Folder 485)
  - Techno-Durham. Stagville, 2000 July 11 (Box 43, Folder 486)
  - YDD - World Wide Colors (1st Session) Parra, Casilda. Durham. El Centro Hispano. 2001 June 1 (Box 44, Folder 487)
  - YDD 2001 - World Wide Colors. (1st session) Mall Interviews 2001 June 1 (Box 44, Folder 488)
  - YDD 2001 - World Wide Colors. (1st Session) Mall Interviews 2001 June 1 (Box 44, Folder 489)
  - YDD 2001 - World Wide Colors. (1st session) Githens Middle School 2001 June 1 (Box 44, Folder 490)
  - YDD 2001 - World Wide Colors. (1st session) Sims-McCreary, Amber. Durham. 2001 June 1 (Box 44, Folder 491)
  - YDD 2001 - World Wide Colors. (1st Session) Bromberg-Seltzer, Bruce. Durham. Rabbi at Hillel. 2001 June 1 (Box 44, Folder 492)
  - YDD 2001 - World Wide Colors. (1st Session) Lenartz, Hans. Durham. Immigration Lawyer. 2001 June 1 (Box 44, Folder 493)
  - YDD 2001 - World Wide Colors. (1st Session) Human Relations Forum on Crime and Race Durham. 2001 June 1 (Box 44, Folder 494)
  - YDD 2001 - World Wide Colors. Ninth Street, Durham. 2001 June 1 (Box 44, Folder 495)
  - YDD 2001 - Jobs that Pay. Riley, Ginger. Durham. Banker. (Box 45, Folder 496)
  - YDD 2001 - Jobs that Pay. Stallings, Dennis. RTP. Principal Architect for The Freelon Group Inc. 2001 July 17 (Box 45, Folder 497)
  - YDD 2001 - Jobs that Pay. Dolish, Mark. Durham. Photo Assignment Editor. 2001 July 20 (Box 45, Folder 498)
  - YDD 2001 - Jobs that Pay. Miranda-Watkins, Francis. Durham. Attorney. 2001 July 20 (Box 45, Folder 498)
  - YDD 2001 - Jobs that Pay. Bowser, Najesta. Housekeeper for Duke University. 2001 July 10 (Box 45, Folder 499)
  - YDD 2001 - Jobs that Pay. Dimler, Tom. Durham. Employee of the Boy Scouts of America. 2001 July 18 (Box 45, Folder 500)
  - YDD 2001 - Jobs that Pay. Salvador, Melissa. Durham. Accountant. 2001 July 11 (Box 45, Folder 501)
  - YDD 2001 - Jobs that Pay. Hill, Willie. Durham. Record Producer, Musician. 2001 July 18 (Box 45, Folder 502)
  - YDD 2001 - Jobs that Pay. Dula, Suzzette. Gymnastics Instructor. 2001 July 10 (Box 45, Folder 503)
  - YDD 2001 - Jobs that Pay __________ Adrianna. Waitress. 2001 July 11 (Box 46, Folder 504)
  - YDD 2001 - Jobs that Pay(Respondent's name unknown.) Graphic Clothing Printer. 2001 July 11 (Box 46, Folder 505)
    Interview of collector's (Perla Parra's) aunt (last name Chavez?). Respondent only speaks Spanish.
  - YDD 2001 - Jobs that Pay. Gus, Holley. Durham, West Campus. Career Counselor at Duke Career Center. 2001 July 12 (Box 46, Folder 506)
  - YDD 2001 - World Wide Colors. (2nd Session) Revelle, Victoria, and Truong, Rosey. Durham. 2001 July 10 (Box 46, Folder 507)
  - YDD 2001 - World Wide Colors. Mujahid, Muna. Durham, East Durham. 2001 July 9 (Box 46, Folder 508)
  - YDD 2001 - World Wide Colors. (2nd Session) Hynos? Florencia. Durham. 2001 July 10 (Box 46, Folder 509)
  - YDD 2001 - World Wide Colors. (2nd Session) Group Interviews. Durham. 2001 July 16 (Box 46, Folder 510)
  - YDD 2001 - World Wide Colors. (2nd Session) Durham, Debbie. Durham, East Campus. Manager of One World Market. 2001 July 18 (Box 46, Folder 511)
  - YDD 2001 - World Wide Colors. (2nd Session) Olave, Katushka. Durham. 2001 July 18 (Box 46, Folder 512)
  - YDD 2001 - World Wide Colors. (2nd session) Johnson, Lawrence, and Harvard, Joe. Durham. 2001 July 18 (Box 47, Folder 513)
  - YDD 2001 - World Wide Colors. (2nd Session) Cliette, Amina, and Serrano, Myrna. Durham. 2001 July 10 (Box 47, Folder 514)
  - YDD 2001 - World Wide Colors. (2nd session) Martinez, Magdalena, and Abby, Jacqueta. Durham. 2001 July 10 (Box 47, Folder 515)
  - YDD 2001 - World Wide Colors. (2nd Session) Cliette, Amina, and Truong, Rosey. Durham. 2001 July 9 (Box 47, Folder 516)
  - YDD 2001 - Jobs that Pay. Harkrador, Lonna. Entrepreneur and Real Estate Agent. (Box 47, Folder 517)
  - YDD 2001 - Jobs that Pay. Lowe, James. Heart Surgeon. (Box 47, Folder 517)
  - YDD 2001 - Why Teens Fight. (1st session) Goodhand, Meg. Durham. Teacher. (Box 47, Folder 518)
  - YDD 2001 - Why Teens Fight. (1st session) Fernandez, Khameo, and Ionescu, Sarah. Durham. (Box 47, Folder 518)
  - YDD 2001 - Why Teens Fight. (1st session) Police Station. Durham. (Box 47, Folder 519)
  - YDD 2001 - Why Teens Fight. (1st session) Lakeveiw School. Durham. (Box 47, Folder 520)
  - YDD 2001 - Jobs that Pay. Career Development Center. Durham. 2001 June 19 (Box 47, Folder 521)
  - YDD 2001 - Jobs that Pay (1st session) Bank Trip. Durham. 2001 June 25 (Box 48, Folder 522)
  - YDD 2001 - Jobs that Pay. (1st session) Wells, Ilene. Durham. Nurse. (Box 48, Folder 523)
  - YDD 2001 - Why Teens Fight. (2nd session) Group Interview. Durham. (Box 48, Folder 524)
  - YDD 2001 - Jobs that Pay. Thornton, Pamela. Durham. Deli employee. (Box 48, Folder 525)
  - YDD 2001 - Jobs that Pay. (1st session) Anglin, Peggy. Durham. Physical Therapist. 2008 June 1 (Box 48, Folder 526)
  - YDD 2001 - Jobs that Pay. (1st session) Revelle, Bernice. Durham. Paralegal Agent. (Box 48, Folder 527)
  - YDD 2001 - Why Teens Fight.Street Interviews Durham. 2008 June 1 (Box 48, Folder 528)
  - YDD 2001 - Why Teens Fight. Patterson, Rokesha. Durham. (Box 48, Folder 529)
  - YDD 2001 - Why Teens Fight. (2nd Session) Jackson, Francis. Durham. Owner of FJ’s Emporium. 2001 July 20 (Box 48, Folder 530)
  - YDD 2001 - Why Teens Fight. (2nd Session) Thorpe, Paulette. Durham. 2001 July 10 (Box 48, Folder 531)
  - YDD 2001 - Why Teens FightStreet Interview Brian. Durham. 2001 July 10[File 532 is missing from container.] (Box 49, Folder 532)
  - YDD 2001 - Why Teens Fight. (2nd Session) Eddie. Durham. Owner of Dogstar Tatoo Parlor. 2001 July 10 [File 532 is missing from container.] (Box 49, Folder 532)
  - YDD Islac, Kevin, and Edith. 2002 July 9 (Box 49, Folder 533)
  - YDD Childress, Emily. Middle School Student. (Box 49, Folder 534)
  - YDD Elementary Student. (Box 49, Folder 535)
  - YDD-Youth Power. Session 2 Revelle, Bernice. 2002 Summer (Box 49, Folder 536)
  - YDD--Cultural Collage. 1st session Andrews, Joanne. Ceramics Teacher. 2002 Summer (Box 49, Folder 537)
  - YDD -Cultural Collage. 1st session Teacher and students at MacDougal Terrace. 2002 Summer (Box 49, Folder 538)
  - YDD-Cultural Collage. Session 1 Brubeck, Maria. SEEDS Employee. 2002 Summer (Box 49, Folder 539)
  - YDD-Cultural Collage. Session 1 Matlock, Earl. Gardener at DIG. 2002 Summer (Box 49, Folder 540)
  - YDD-Cultural Collage. Session 1 Milne, Amy. Manager of the See-Saw Studio. 2002 Summer (Box 49, Folder 542)
  - YDD-Youth Power. Session 2 Cliette, Musa. Middle school student. 2002 July 10 (Box 49, Folder 543)
  - YDD-Youth Power-Session 1 Lopez, Danny. Student. 2002 Summer (Box 50, Folder 544)
  - YDD- Youth Power. Galban, Rosa. House Cleaner. 2008 June 12 (Box 50, Folder 545)
  - YDD-High Tech World. Session 2 Students. 2002 Summer (Box 50, Folder 546)
  - YDD-High Tech World. Session 2 Davis, Jon. Technology Coordinator at NC School of Math and Science. 2002 Summer (Box 50, Folder 547)
  - YDD-High Tech World. Session 2 Miss Janette. Teacher. 2002 Summer (Box 50, Folder 548)
  - YDD-High Tech World. Session 2 Case, June. Grandmother and Day Care Staff Member. 2002 Summer (Box 50, Folder 549)
  - YDD-High Tech World. Session 1 2002 Summer (Box 50, Folder 550)
  - YDD-High Tech World. Session 1 Joyce, Johnny. Security Officer at RDU Airport. 2002 Summer (Box 50, Folder 551)
  - YDD-High Tech World. Session 1 Steele, Quin. Student. 2002 Summer (Box 50, Folder 552)
  - YDD-High Tech World. Session 1 Student. 2002 Summer (Box 50, Folder 553)
  - YDD-Cultural Collage. Session 2 2002 Summer (Box 50, Folder 554)
  - YDD-Cultural Collage. Session 2 2002 Summer (Box 50, Folder 555)
  - YDD-Cultural Collage. Session 2 Ponce, Pablo.radio DJ at a Latino radio station 2002 Summer (Box 50, Folder 556)
  - YDD-Youth Power. Session 1 Scott, Christina. Student. 2002 Summer (Box 50, Folder 557)
  - YDD Youth Power. Session 1 Vaughn, Margaret. Teacher. 2002 Summer (Box 50, Folder 558)
  - YDD-Youth Power. Session 1 Karima. Student. 2002 Summer (Box 50, Folder 559)
  - YDD-Youth Power. Session 1 Lawrence, Wendy. Teacher. 2002 Summer (Box 50, Folder 560)
  - YDD-Youth Power. Session 1 Lyons, Barbara. MacDougall Terrace Resident Council President. 2002 Summer (Box 50, Folder 561)
  - YDD-Youth Power. Session 1 2002 Summer (Box 50, Folder 562)
  - YDD-Youth Power-Session 2 NAACP Worker. 2002 Summer (Box 51, Folder 563)
  - YDD-Youth Power. Session 2 Police Officer. 2002 Summer (Box 51, Folder 564)
  - YDD- Youth Power. Session 2 Jackson, Francis. Police Officer. 2002 Summer (Box 51, Folder 565)
  - YDD-Youth Power. Session 2 NAACP Worker. 2002 Summer (Box 51, Folder 566)
  - YDD-Cultural Collage. Session 2 Alston, Crystal. Facility Coordinator for Durham Arts Council. 2002 Summer (Box 51, Folder 567)
  - YDD-Cultural Collage. Session 2 Davis, Chuck. Artistic Director of African American Dance Ensemble. 2002 Summer (Box 51, Folder 568)
  - YDD-Cultural Collage. Session 2 2002 Summer (Box 51, Folder 569)
  - YDD-Cultural Collage. Session 2 Seykar, Sady. Cashier at McDonald's Drugstore. 2002 Summer (Box 51, Folder 570)
  - YDD-Cultural Collage. Session 2 Steven. NY Pizza Employee. 2002 Summer (Box 51, Folder 571)
  - YDD-Cultural Collage. Session 2 Parker, Roxanne. Pottery Painting Store Employee. 2002 Summer (Box 51, Folder 572)
  - YDD-Cultural Collage. Session 2 Margaret. Retail Store Staff Member. 2002 Summer (Box 51, Folder 573)
  - YDD-Cultural Collage. Session 2 Colleen. Park Ranger. 2002 Summer (Box 51, Folder 574)
  - YDD-High Tech World. Session 2 Dobie, Billy. Retired. 2002 Summer (Box 51, Folder 575)
  - YDD-Youth Power. Torres, Oscar. Student. 2008 June 12 (Box 51, Folder 576)
  - YDD- Youth Power. Rush, Natasha. Social Worker at Child Support. (Box 51, Folder 577)
  - YDD-Youth Power. (Box 51, Folder 578)
  - YDD 2002-Youth Power. Shershanovich, Carrie. 2002 June 24 (Box 51, Folder 579)
  - YDD-2002, Youth Power. Willeford, James. Guidance Counselor. 2002 June 12 (Box 51, Folder 580)
  - YDD 2002--Youth Power. 2002 June 11 (Box 51, Folder 581)
  - YDD 2002. Terry, Eddie. Student. Summer (Box 51, Folder 582)
  - YDD 2002. Kenneth, and Aaron. Students. Summer (Box 51, Folder 583)
  - YDD 2002. Summer (Box 51, Folder 584)
  - YDD 2002. 2002 June 13 (Box 51, Folder 585)
  - YDD 2002 Summer (Box 52, Folder 586)
  - YDD 2002- Cultural Collage. Van, Mitchell. Facilities Manager at Durham Arts Council. Summer (Box 52, Folder 587)
  - YDD 2002. Tequayla. Middle School Student. Summer (Box 52, Folder 588)
  - YDD 2002--Youth Power. Plesser, Amy. Summer (Box 52, Folder 589)
  - YDD 2002. Marcus. Student. Summer (Box 52, Folder 590)
  - YDD 2002. Chandrea.student at Chewning Middle School 2002 May 12 (Box 52, Folder 591)
  - YDD 2002. Barry. Student. Summer (Box 52, Folder 592)
  - YDD 2002. Students. Summer (Box 52, Folder 593)
  - YDD 2002. Chandrea. Student.2002 (Box 52, Folder 594)
  - YDD 2002. Summer (Box 52, Folder 595)
  - YDD 2002. Torres, Gabriella. Student. 2002 June 17 (Box 52, Folder 596)
  - YDD 2002. Students. 2002 June 19 (Box 52, Folder 597)
  - Durham Works. Githens MS 2002-03 Martinez, Miguel. Durham. Freelance Photographer. (Box 52, Folder 598)
  - Durham Works. Githens MS 2002-03 Espinoza, Cristobal. Engineer at IBM. (Box 52, Folder 599)
  - Durham Works. Githens MS 2002-03 Portillo, Idalia. Durham. Manager of Latino Credit Union. (Box 52, Folder 600)
  - Durham Works. Edison Johnson Recreation Center 2002 DeLoatch, Lois. Durham. Duke Library. Fundraiser, Singer. (Box 53, Folder 601)
  - Durham Works. Edison Johnson Rec Ctr 2002 Spense, Phil. Durham. Head Basketball Coach at NCCU. (Box 53, Folder 602)
  - Durham Works. Edison Johnson Rec Ctr. 2002 Kleelich, Elimar. Durham. Chef at George’s Garage. (Box 53, Folder 603)
  - YDD 2002-Youth Forum on Media Youth. Media Professionals. Students and Television Reporters. 2002 Aug. 21 (Box 53, Folder 604)
  - YDD 2002-Youth Forum on Media Youth. Media Professionals. Students, Radio Producers, and Newspaper Editors. 2002 Aug. 21 (Box 53, Folder 605)
  - YDD 2002-Youth Forum on Media Youth. Media Representatives. Students, Newspaper Editors, Television Program Coordinator, and Documentary Program Coordinators 2002 Aug. 21 (Box 53, Folder 606)
  - Durham Works. Taylor, Chandra. Lawyer. 2003 Mar. 1 (Box 53, Folder 607)
  - Durham Works. School Administrators and Teachers. 2003 Mar. 1 (Box 53, Folder 608)
  - Durham Works. Fulla, Mahasahra. Gallery Coordinator.2003 (Box 53, Folder 609)
  - Coffin, Patricia. Durham. 1998 July 13 (Box 53, Folder 610)
  - Fox, Mary. Durham. 1998 July 21 (Box 53, Folder 611)
  - Tobacco Talk. Poteat, Vertee. Durham. 1998 July 23 (Box 53, Folder 612)
  - YDD 2001 - Jobs that Pay. Willeford, James. Durham. High School Guidance Counselor. 2001 June 19 (Box 53, Folder 613)
- Photographic Materials Series, 2000-2006, (7 boxes)
  A visual narration of "Community Stories" through the original photography of Youth Document Durham participants. Images focus on specific topics chosen by the program staff for each session. The series is separated into two subseries: Contact Sheets and Negatives, and Photographic Prints. The first contains contact sheets and scanned negative images from 2000-2006. The second subseries contains photographic prints from 1996 to 2006, but other materials can be found with these prints, including contact sheets and scanned negative images from 1997-1999. All are arranged in chronological order by program session.
  Other photographs and associated a/v materials can be found in the Project Files Series, chiefly in the Exhibits and Project Subseries.
  - Contact Sheets and Negatives Subseries, 2000-2006, (3 boxes)
    Folders are arranged alphabetically by topic within each session. Some project descriptions and other written information are included in corresponding chronological groups. Other contact sheets and negatives from earlier years can be found in the Prints subseries.
    - 2000 June (Box 54)
      - Durham Eats (Box 54)
      - Sounds of a City (Box 54)
    - 2000 July
      - Crime Group (Box 54)
      - Durham Eats (Box 54)
      - Techno Durham (Box 54)
    - 2001 June
      - Jobs That Pay (Box 54)
      - Why Teens Fight (Box 54)
      - World Wide Colors (Box 54)
    - 2001 July
      - Jobs That Pay (Box 54)
      - Why Teens Fight (Box 54)
      - World Wide Colors (Box 54)
    - 2002 June (Box 55)
      - Cultural Collage (Box 55)
      - Youth Power (Box 55)
    - 2002 July
      - Cultural Collage (Box 55)
      - High Tech World (Box 55)
      - Youth Power (Box 55)
    - 2003 June
      - Breaking News: Media Mis-Understandings (Box 55)
      - Race Matters (Box 55)
      - Let's Talk About It: Sex Education and Health (Box 55)
    - 2003 July
      - Breaking News: Media Mis-Understandings (Box 55)
      - Race Matters (Box 55)
      - Let's Talk About It: Sex Education and Health (Box 55)
    - 2004 June
      - Youth Culture: Seen and Heard (Box 55)
      - Youth Culture: Seen and Heard, Photo Group (Box 56)
    - 2004 July
      - Fight For Your Rights/Rock The Boat: Politics and Justice (Box 56)
      - Fight For Your Rights/Rock The Boat: Politics and Justice, Photo Group (Box 56)
    - 2005 June
      - Generation Mix: Love and Culture in Durham (Box 56)
    - 2005 July
      - Moving In The 919: Bull City Bus Stories (Box 56)
    - 2006 June-July
      - Teen Life: Growing Up In Durham (Box 56)
  - Photographic Prints Subseries, 1996-2006, (4 boxes)
    Files contain photographs of various sizes, both black-and-white and color. Prints from 1996-1999 are accompanied by negative and contact sheets, two VHS cassettes, one CD-ROM (1998-1999), and administrative records. The 1996 videocassette holds raw material from the Community Stories project; the 1997 videocassette is a final piece from a project in Summerton, S.C. The folders are organized chronologically.
    [Original recordings are closed to use. Viewing or listening copies must be produced before contents can be accessed. Electronic files have been mounted on the library server. Please consult with a reference archivist before coming to use this material.]
    - Summer 1996, (1 folder, 1 videocassette) (Box 57)
    - Summer 1997, (4 folders, 1 videocassette) (Box 57)
    - Summer 1998, (1-4 of 7 folders) (Box 57)
    - 1998, (5-7 of 7 folders) (Box 58)
    - Summer 1999, (1-12 of 20 folders) (Box 58)
    - Summer 1999, (13-20 of 20 folders) (Box 59)
    - 2005, (3 folders) (Box 59)
    - 2006, (1 folder) (Box 60)
    - Prints for retrospective book, (10 folders) (Box 60)
- Project Files Series, 1995-2006 and undated, (6 boxes)
  Contains various administrative papers, program information, participant forms, electronic final projects, published materials derived from each project, and many informal photographs documenting various events and individual activities during the program sessions. Also associated with these materials are many digital files of student work, curriculum, and other program documentation.
  - Curriculum Files Subseries, 1995-2006 and undated, (2 boxes)
    Boxes contain office files belonging to the program staff, chiefly comprised of staff meeting notes, applications and other forms, participant lists, itineraries, activities and lesson plans, reading materials, and some assignments. These boxes also contained five CDs housing YDD program files, one for each year, and five MDs of audio and one digital DV of student work from various programs. Additionally, one CD contains files from the early Community Stories projects of 1995 and 1999. Discs have been separated from the collection and the files mounted to a server. Arranged chronologically by year and within alphabetically by session name if applicable.
    [Electronic records have been migrated to a library server. To request access, please contact a reference archivist before coming to use this collection.]
    - 1995, 1999, 2000 (Box 61)
      - General Curriculum (Box 61)
      - Photo Curriculum (Box 61)
    - 2001
      - General Curriculum (Box 61)
    - 2002
      - Cultural Collage Group (Box 61)
      - High Tech World Group (Box 61)
      - Youth Power Group (Box 61)
    - 2003
      - Breaking News: Media Misunderstands Group (Box 61)
      - Color Coded: Race Matters Group (Box 61)
      - Let's Talk About It: Sex Education and Health (Box 61)
    - 2004
      - General Curriculum (Box 61)
    - 2005 (Box 62)
      - General Curriculum (Box 62)
      - Session 2 Curriculum (Box 62)
    - 2006
      - General Curriculum (Box 62)
  - Exhibits and Projects Subseries, circa 1998-2006, (3 boxes)
    Files contain promotional materials for Youth Document Durham and Youth Noise Network programs and exhibitions (one folder), and photographic prints, slides, negatives, and contact sheets that document the students' final displays (ten folders). The slides include not only the exhibit layout and opening, but also contain the student's own images used in the exhibit. There is one set of 84 8x10 and 5x7 inch prints (three folders) used in the Together in our Neighborhood/Juntos con Nuestra Herencia exhibit in 1999. Printed snapshots, news clippings and other publicity also accompany project materials. DVDs and CDs, separated from the collection and mounted on a library server, contain digital movies, audio, images, and text from student final projects and exhibits from 2005-2006.
    - Publicity materials, 2001-2004 and undated (Box 62)
    - Together With Our Community/Juntos con Nuestra Herencia, CDS exhibit publicity materials, 1999 (Box 62)
    - Together With Our Community/Juntos con Nuestra Herencia, exhibit prints, circa 1998-1999, (84 items) (Box 74)
      The prints, which were used in the exhibit, often have caption labels with titles in Spanish and English. A set of slides of the same images accompany the exhibit photographs. There may also be additional images in the slides group that do not have corresponding prints and vice versa.
    - In My Community: Documenting Changing Lives In Durham, exhibit materials, 2000 (Box 62)
    - In My Community: Documenting Changing Lives In Durham, large paper reproductions of photographic print, 2000, (16.5 x 23.5 in.) (Opaperfolder 1)